Register of the Joseph Coy Green Papers, 1914-1957
Hoover Institution Archives
Joseph Coy Green Papers,
1914-1957
56025
Green, Joseph C., 1887-1978
21 manuscript boxes, 2 envelopes. (8.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Diary, correspondence, writings, reports, pamphlets, clippings, maps, and printed matter, relating to the Commission for Relief in Belgium, American Relief Administration activities in Romania and Transcaucasia, and the Herbert Hoover-for-President campaign in 1920.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Commission for Relief in Belgium (1914-1930); American Relief Administration.; International relief.; Presidents--United States--Election--1920.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1914-1918--Civilian relief.; Armenia (Republic)--History.; Armenia (Republic); Belgium.; Georgia (Republic)--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.; Georgia (Republic); Romania.; Romania--History.; Soviet Union.; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921--Civilian relief.; United States--Politics and government.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Politics and government--20th century.
Biographical Note
1887, April 12 Born, Cincinnati, Ohio
1908 A.B., Princeton
1909 A.M., Princeton
1909-1910 Graduate studies, University of Grenoble and University of Paris
1910-1911 Instructor, History, Bordentown Military Institute
1911-1913 Instructor, History, Columbia University
1915-1917 Chief of Inspection for Belgium and Occupied Areas of France, Commission for Relief in Belgium
1918-1919 Director for Romania and later the Near East, American Relief Administration
1920 Chairman, Ohio Committee for the election of Herbert Hoover.
1920-1924 Assistant Professor of History, Princeton
1924-1930 Associate Professor of History, Princeton
1930-1935 Assistant, Division of Western European Affairs, State Department
1931-1942 Chairman, Committee to Revise Foreign Service Examinations
1935-1939 Chief, Office of Arms and Munitions Control
1939-1941 Chief, Division of Controls
1935-1946 Executive Secretary, National Munitions Control Board
1941-1944 Special Assistant to the Secretary of State
1944-1946 Advisor on Arms and Munitions Controls
1946-1952 Chairman, Advisory Committee on Foreign Service Examinations
1952-1953 Ambassador to Jordan
1978 died
Series Description
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1914-1929. (Box Boxes 1-2)
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
- SUBJECT FILE, 1914-1957. (Box Boxes 3-20)
  Reports, memoranda, and printed material relating primarily to Joseph C. Green's association with the Commission for Relief in Belgium, the American Relief Administration, and the Ohio State Committee for Herbert Hoover in the presidential compaign of 1920. Materials are arranged alphabetically by title or subject.
- WRITINGS, ca. 1917. (Box 20)
  Manuscripts of brief articles by Joseph C. Green containing his impressions of his experiences in Belgium.
- DIARY, 1915-1917. (Box 20)
  Typewritten selections from the Joseph C. Green diaries.
- MISCELLANY, ca. 1917-1918. (Box 21)
  European maps, aerial photographs, bank notes, paper coins.
- AUDIO-VISUAL.
  See photo card catalog.
Container List
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1914-1929
  - General, 1917-1929 (Box 1)
  - Unidentified, 1918
  - Allen, Ben S., 1918
  - Andrews, Capt., 1919
  - Bowden, C. G., 1917
  - Bristol, Mark L., 1919
  - Brough, A., n.d.
  - Brown, Harry W., 1917-1926
  - Brown, Milton M., 1916-1920
  - Bush, Norman, 1921
  - Butler, Howard Crosby, 1917
  - Carpe, Bertha, 1919
  - Chapman, Percy A., 1917
  - Chevrillon, Louis, 1917
  - Cruger, Alexander, 1917
  - Curtis, E. D., 1917
  - Davignon, Henri, 1917
  - DeGrunne, Willy, 1917
  - Eckstein, Fred, 1917
  - Forbes, C. Stewart, 1919
  - Gailor, F. H., 1917-1918
  - Galpin, Perrin C., 1920-1921
  - Gibson, Hugh, 1918-1920
  - Goldsmith, Alan, 1919
  - Green, Mrs. and Mrs. James A., 1914-1918
  - Green, Mrs. and Mrs. James A., 1919-1929 (Box 2)
  - Green, Robert M., 1916-1920
  - Haskell, William N., 1919
  - Heinz, Howard, 1920
  - Hoover, President Herbert C., 1919-1920
  - Jackson, R. A., 1917-1920
  - Kauffman, Reginald W., 1919
  - Khatissian, Prime Minister of Armenia, 1919
  - Kittredge, Tracy, 1921
  - Logan, James A., 1919
  - McElroy, Robert, 1917
  - Maurice, Arthur, 1918
  - Moore, Benjamin B., 1920
  - Morris, J. C., 1919-1920
  - Osborn, E. D., 1917-1918
  - Paradise, Scott H., 1917
  - Peden, E. A., 1919
  - Percy, Eustace, 1917
  - Pers, Jean, 1917
  - Pittenger, C. H., 1920
  - Poland, W. B., 1917-1920
  - Richards, Lewis, 1917-1918
  - Shaler, Millard, 1918
  - Shipman, Harry R., 1917
  - Simpson, John L., 1919
  - Smith, Baldwin, 1917
  - Smith, Robinson, 1917
  - Souriau, Jacques, 1917
  - Taft, Robert A., 1919-1920
  - Torrey, Clare M., 1918-1920
  - Treat, Albert W., 1920
  - Tuck, W. H., 1915-1920
  - Van Dyke, Paul, 1917-1919
  - Van Dyke, Tertius, 1917
  - Vickery, Charles V., 1919
  - Wellington, L. C., 1917-1920
  - Whitlock, Brand, 1917
  - Wickes, F. C., 1918
  - Yates, Col., 1919
- SUBJECT FILE, 1914-1957
  - American Hospital of Paris, Annual Reports, 1917, 1918, 1919, (1 volume) (Box 3)
  - Belgian pamphlets (bound)
  - Belgium
    - Comite National de Secours et d'Alimentation (National Committee for Relief and Food)
      - Comite Executive (Executive Committee)
        - November, 1914
        - December, 1915
      - Miscellany
      - Provincial Reports
        - Anvers
        - Brabant
        - Hainaut
        - Limbourg
      - Rapport - Juillet, Aout et Septembre, 1915 (Report - July, August, and September, 1915)
    - Ministere de l'Interieur - Annuaire Statistique 1913 (Ministry of the Interior - Statistical Yearbook, 1913) (Box 4)
    - Ministry of Justice and Ministry of Foreign Affairs - "War of 1914-1916"
  - Biographical material
  - Bulletin des Francais - March - July, 1915 (pamphlet)
  - Bunge, Edouard G.
  - Caucasus and Daghestan
  - Commission for Relief in Belgium, 1914-1923
    - General
    - Miscellany
    - Reports
      - Annual Report (First), 1914-1915
      - Annual Report (Second), 1914-1916 (Box 5)
      - Balance Sheet and Accounts, 1914-1920
      - Belgian Section
      - "Clothing the Destitute of Belgium and the North of France"
      - Northern France
      - "Notes on Pacification," 1916
      - "Purchase and Transportation of Foodstuffs," 1915
      - Rapport Annuel, Premier, (First Annual Report), 1914-1915
      - Rapport Annuel, Second, (Second Annual Report), 1917 (Box 6)
      - Relief Appropriations
      - Statistical Bulletin
    - Department of Inspection and Control
    - Deportation of Men
      - Document #1
      - Document #2
      - Document #3
    - Directory of Members
  - European War, 1914-1918 (Box 7)
    - General
      - Maps
      - Miscellaneous printed material
    - "Allemands Destructeurs, Les" (The German Destroyers) (Box 8)
    - American Expeditionary Forces
      - Army Regulations, 1917-1918 (incomplete)
      - Digest of Opinions of the Judge Advocate General of the Army, 1918 (incomplete)
      - General Orders
        - 1917
        - 1918 (Box 9)
      - Miscellany
      - Press office
    - Avis, Proclamations and Nouvelles de Guerre, Les (Opinions, Proclamations and News of the War), Historical souvenir booklets
      - Volumes 1-5
      - Volumes 6-10
      - Volumes 11-16 (Box 10)
    - "Etudes et Documents sur la Guerre" (Studies and Documents on the War), 3 pamphlets, 1915
    - Facts About the War, December, 1914-May, 1915
  - Hoover, Herbert
    - General
      - American Institute of Mining Engineers. Hoover's Inauguration Address, February 17, 1920
      - Industrial Conference Report, 1920
      - Overseas and War Service Organizations, 1914-1924., Pamphlet
      - United States Food Administration Report, 1920 (Introduction)
    - Political Campaign, 1920
      - General
      - Alternate delegates (card file and lists)
      - Campaign committee members (lists)
      - Campaign materials
        - Information about Herbert Hoover
        - Literature (Box 11)
        - Orders, receipts, etc.
        - Songs
      - Campaign plans
      - Campaign statements by Hoover supporters
      - Cincinnati Post - letters to the editor
      - Convention
      - Delegate lists
      - Election tabulations
      - Hoover clubs
      - Hoover, Herbert
        - Campaign statements, speeches
        - Correspondence
      - Miscellany
      - National committee
      - Newsletters
        - Daily News Letter, April - May, 1920 (incomplete)
        - Hoover National Bulletin, March - May, 1920 (incomplete)
        - News About Hoover, March, 1920 (incomplete)
      - Newspaper support (Box 12)
      - Ohio Committee
        - General
        - Correspondence
          - Form letters
          - Postcards (Box 13)
          - Anti-Hoover candidacy (Box 14)
          - County file
            - Allen
            - Ashtabula
            - Athens
            - Auglaize
            - Butler
            - Clark
            - Clinton
            - Coshocton
            - Crawford
            - Cuyahoga
            - Delaware
            - Erie
            - Fairfield
            - Franklin
            - Fulton
            - Greene
            - Guernsey
            - Henry
            - Huron
            - Jefferson
            - Knox
            - Lake
            - Lorain
            - Lucas
            - Madison
            - Mahoning
            - Medina
            - Meigs
            - Miami
            - Montgomery
            - Morrow
            - Muskingum
            - Portage
            - Richmond
            - Rose
            - Sandusky (Box 15)
            - Scioto
            - Stark
            - Summit
            - Trumbull
            - Tuscarawas
            - Union
            - Warren
            - Washington
            - Wayne
            - Wood
          - Hoover Clubs
          - Individual file
            - Arnold, Ralph
            - Baker, George Barr
            - Barnard, H. E.
            - Barnes, Julius H.
            - Ellis, T. A.
            - Hallowell, John W.
            - Henderson, C. T.
            - Jenson, J.
            - Jones, John Price
            - Lucey, J. F. (Box 16)
            - Pearson, J. W.
            - Pratt, Florence
            - Taft, Robert A.
            - Westwater, James
          - Women
        - Petitions
        - Press releases, statements (Box 17)
        - Publicity
        - State chairmen (lists)
        - Voters
          - Card file
          - Lists of Hoover supporters
  - McKinley, William
  - Marie, Queen of Romania
  - Miscellaneous printed material
  - United Nations - Charter
  - United States (Box 18)
    - American Relief Administration, 1917-1923
      - General
        - Bulletin
          - October, 1920 - August, 1921 (incomplete)
          - September, 1921 - January, 1922
        - Memoranda
      - Mission to the Near East
        - General - Final Report
        - Hoover, Herbert
        - "With the A.R.A. in Roumania" by Robert Green
    - Department of State - International Traffic in Arms, 1935-1942 (booklets) (Box 19)
    - Foreign service personnel, 1949
    - House of Representatives
      - Department of State Appropriations Bill, 1942
      - Hearings on American Neutrality Policy
      - Hearings on Exportation of Arms or Munitions of War, 1933
      - National Munitions Act (contains statement by Joseph C. Green)
      - National Munitions Control Board, Annual Reports, 1936-1940
    - Senate
      - Committee on Government Operations, 1957
      - Hearings on the Middle East, 1957 (Box 20)
      - Report on the Middle East, 1957
  - Whitlock, Brand
  - Wilson, Woodrow
- WRITINGS, ca. 1917
  - Belgium. Manuscripts of articles by Joseph C. Green containing his impressions of his experiences in Belgium. (Box 20)
- DIARY, 1915-1917
  - Typewritten selections from Joseph C. Green diaries (Box 20)
- MISCELLANY, ca. 1917-1918
  - Maps of Europe (Box 21)
  - Aerial photos of Europe
  - Bank notes, paper coins, billfold
- AUDIO-VISUAL.
  See photo card catalog